Neighbor. Icon. Friend.
A Beautiful Day in the Neighborhood is a history, family,
drama film directed by Marielle Heller.
An award-winning cynical journalist, Lloyd Vogel, begrudgingly accepts an assignment to
write an Esquire profile piece on the beloved television icon Fred Rogers.
After his encounter with Rogers, Vogel's perspective on life is transformed.
Lloyd Vogel, played by Matthew Rhys.
Fred Rogers, played by Tom Hanks.
Jerry Vogel, played by Chris Cooper.
Andrea Vogel, played by Susan Kelechi Watson.
Joanne Rogers, played by Maryann Plunkett.
Bill Isler, played by Enrico Colantoni.
A Beautiful Day in the Neighborhood is a 2019 American biographical drama film on the TV host Fred Rogers, directed by
Marielle Heller and written by Micah Fitzerman-Blue and Noah Harpster, inspired by the 1998 article "Can You Say ...
Hero?" by Tom Junod, published in Esquire.
It stars Tom Hanks, Matthew Rhys, Susan Kelechi Watson, and Chris Cooper.
It depicts Lloyd Vogel (Rhys), a troubled journalist for Esquire who is
assigned to profile television icon Fred Rogers (Hanks).
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 7, 2019, and was
theatrically released in the United States on November 22, 2019, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
It grossed $68 million worldwide.
Critics praised Hanks and Rhys's performances, Heller's
direction, and its heart-warming messages.
It was chosen by Time magazine as one of the ten best films of the year.
For his performance, Hanks was nominated for Best Supporting Actor at the Academy Awards, as well as the
Golden Globes, Critics' Choice, Screen Actors Guild Awards, and BAFTA Awards, among others.
The film explores themes of friendship, male friendship,
based on true story, kindness, estranged father.
The tone is emotional.